<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Satya Knowledge</title>
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com" />
    <updated>2020-03-20T18:09:34+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Narender Singh</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Liberals and Marxists - Liberalism And Marxism Politics</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/liberals-and-marxists.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/liberals-and-marxists.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-20T18:09:21+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/26/2000px-Forms_of_government.svg.png" alt="Liberals and Marxists" />
                    Some political thinkers think that liberty and equality cannot go together. They think that liberty implies the freedom to do what one would like to do. This is true if freedom is interpreted in its absolute sense to mean that every individual shall be free&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/26/2000px-Forms_of_government.svg.png" alt="Liberals and Marxists" />
                <p>Some political thinkers think that liberty and equality cannot go together. They think that liberty implies the freedom to do what one would like to do. This is true if freedom is interpreted in its absolute sense to mean that every individual shall be free according to his opportunities, there will be chaos. It is a lesson of history that whenever people are allowed to do as they wish, the clever and more capable used their freedom to con centrate all wealth and power in themselves to the misery and oppression of the rest.</p>
<p>Obviously the negative view is described by those who belong to privileged section of community and for this reason, seek to maintain status quo for the sake of their vested interests. They think that equality is unattainable under conditions of such unrestricted freedom. Lord Acton therefore, says, "The passion of equality made vain the hope of liberty."<br><br>The exponents of this view held that liberty is natural, equality is not. Nature itself created differences. For example, some are intellectuals, others are not. Liberty means freedom i.e., no restrictions : equality needs some restrictions. This is against the prin ciple of liberty. The institution of property is a natural institution and therefore, should not be restricted by equality. Perfect equality is only possible when enforced by state. This means the powers of state will increase.</p>
<p>Excess power of the state is harmful to the liberty of the people. Moreover, state has produced many evils of capitalism. It has encouraged exploitation. It has given protection to the capitalists. Such a state cannot give perfect equality. So, the hope of liberty also vanishes away. The democracy is said to be a system based on liberty and equality. But unfortunately, the democracy is either becoming elites' democracy or dollar democracy. Either this is controlled by the edu cated class or by the capitalist. Presence of elite or capitalist is inequality. Hence liberty and equality appear opposed to each other.</p>
<p>The liberals as well as Marxists have asserted that liberty and equality are not opposed to each other. Liberty has no meaning if it is not enjoyed by all. All may enjoy liberty only when privileged classes are abolished in the society. In a society of unequal, freedom becomes a farce. What is the use of expression of thought, when some are deprived ? A sound public opinion cannot be formed.</p>
<p>That is why R.H. Tawney observes that a large measure of equality, as far from being inimical to liberty, is essential to it." If there is only liberty, there will be anarchy. The liberty will be exploited for personal profits. Dunham writes, "A group of men whose social role consists of taking profits from other people's labour can have no profound belief in equality and fraternity as desired ideals." Thus liberty needs equality, so that there is no concentration of wealth in one or few hands. The Marxists have gone to the extent of saying that liberty and equality are closely related for a classless society. The liberals think that democracy can never be successful till there is perfect liberty with equality. Laski, a champion of liberalism writes, "There cannot, in a word, be democratic government without equality and without democratic government there cannot be freedom."</p>
<p>Democracy is based on political equality. Political equality is not possible without social and economic equality. In the absence of social equality, some Social class will dominate politics and in the absence of economic equality those holding the means of production will dominate politics. So in the absence of social economic equality liberty is just a myth. People may enjoy real liberty only where social and economic equality is established. This will make democracy successful. Thus, we find that liberty without equality is meaningless. We may enjoy liberty only when there is perfect equality. If liberty is to be viewed as positive thing then equality is pre-requisite.</p>
<p>The Marxists clearly stated there is inequality in the society due to the institution of private property. Many contemporary liberal writers expressed the relation between property and equality but Marxists scientifically analysed the question of equality in relation to property. They maintained that a classless society could only be established when private property is abolished. In a classless society one will work according to one's ability and each will get according to one's need.</p>
<p>The Marxists maintain that social and political equality is a myth without economic equality. In the absence of economic equality those holding the means of production will dominate politics. They refuse that the state can create equality in a class divided society through welfare measures. They believe that social ownership of the means of production in a given society is a precondition for economic equality. The Marxists accept that all distinctions cannot be removed. They say, "communist equality presupposes the eradication not of all distinctions and such conditions as would give rise to a difference in the social position of people".</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The art of paying compliments - Real Praise</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/the-art-of-paying-compliments-real-praise.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/the-art-of-paying-compliments-real-praise.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-19T18:18:18+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/25/1__3f0rAE9uPUFeQ2WoguQxw.jpeg" alt="The art of paying compliments" />
                    Real praise, the sincere compliment is probably the most useful social tool of all. It's the valued gold coin of our conversation. Yet today, it is in danger of losing its brightness. For it is greatly misused and not properly exchanged. What is a true&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/25/1__3f0rAE9uPUFeQ2WoguQxw.jpeg" alt="The art of paying compliments" />
                Real praise, the sincere compliment is probably the most useful social tool of all. It's the valued gold coin of our conversation. Yet today, it is in danger of losing its brightness. For it is greatly misused and not properly exchanged. What is a true compliment ? It's one that benefits both giver and receiver. Once a painter and his young assistant were painting our house. The older man was wearing shiny new shoes.<br><br>As the man sta: skilfully painting, my father-in-law, said to the boy, "Son, when you can show up on the job to paint a house, wearing new shoes, you will be the master of your trade." The painter smiled and did the best job. We all like to have our sense of personal worth built up or pointed out. And when one expert adds to another's sense of dignity and speaks favourably of his skill, he is offering a compliment of the highest and rarest kind.<br><br>A compliment differs from flattery in that it is objective and given without thought of gain. Flattery is often merely lip service or excessive praise given for motives other than expressed.<br><br>The greatest efforts of the human race have always resulted from the love of praise. This should be inspired in childhood. The wise parent makes it a point to compliment a child who deserves it. A woman I know has a 12 year old son who considers washing dishes for his mother a great honour. One night, while washing a large dish, it slipped and crashed on the floor. Then his mother said, "You know, Robert, of all the times you have washed the dishes for me, this is the first time you dropped one." Anxiety left the boy's face and he smiled. As one psychologist advises, "Praise virtue and you will find few vices to criticise."<br>There is an art in this giving of compliments. Thus the good compliment is always to the<br><br>point and timing is important. Don't wait too long to tell a person what a good talk he gave or how well he cut your grass. But don't do it immediately when he is expecting it either. Wait. Then when he thinks you may have forgotten, pass the praise.<br><br>Confidence, it has been said, is the greatest gift that one human can give to another. But that does not mean we should be wasteful with our compliments. Rather we should count them carefully remembering that a good compliment has greater purchasing power than money, that no one is too busy or successful to receive a word of praise.<br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e3pd781u0">Summary</h2>
<br>A sincere compliment is the most useful social tool. Unfortunately, it is misused and not properly exchanged. A true compliment benefits both, the giver and the receiver. A compliment is different from flattery. It is objective and without any motive. The love of praise has motivated the greatest achievements of human race. If we praise virtue, we will find few vices to criticise. A good compliment is always precise. Timing is also important. We should not be wasteful with our compliments. A good compliment has more purchasing power than money. Everyone desires and loves to have it.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How does smoking affect your body?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-does-smoking-affect-your-body.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-does-smoking-affect-your-body.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-13T18:50:21+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/24/smoking-kills.jpg" alt="How does smoking affect your body" />
                    Smoking is the major cause of mortality with bronchogenic carcinoma of the lung and is one of the factors causing death due to malignancies of the larynx, oral cavity, esophagus, bladder, kidney, pancreas, stomach, and uterine cervix and coronary heart diseases. Nicotine is the major&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/24/smoking-kills.jpg" alt="How does smoking affect your body" />
                Smoking is the major cause of mortality with bronchogenic carcinoma of the lung and is one of the factors causing death due to malignancies of the larynx, oral cavity, esophagus, bladder, kidney, pancreas, stomach, and uterine cervix and coronary heart diseases. <br><br>Nicotine is the major substance present in the smoke that causes physical dependence. The additives do produce damage to the body - for example, ammonia can result in a 100-fold increase in the ability of nicotine to enter into the smoke. <br><br>Levulinic acid, added to cigarettes to mask the harsh taste of the nicotine, can increase the binding of nicotine to brain receptors, which increases the 'kick' of nicotine. Smoke from the burning end of a cigarette contains over 4000 chemicals and 40 carcinogens. It has long been known that tobacco smoke is carcinogenic or cancer-causing.<br><br>The lungs of smokers collect an annual deposit of 1 to 10 pounds of the gooey black material. The invisible gas phase of cigarette smoke contains nitrogen, oxygen and toxic gases like carbon monoxide, formaldehyde, acrolein, hydrogen cyanide, and nitrogen oxides. These gases are poisonous and in many cases interfere with the body's ability to transport oxygen.<br><br>Like many carcinogenic compounds, they can act as tumor promoters or tumor initiators by acting directly on the genetic make-up of cells the body leading to the development of cancer.<br><br>During smoking within the first 8 - 10 seconds, nicotine is absorbed through the lungs and quickly moved into the bloodstream and circulated throughout the brain. Nicotine can also enter the bloodstream through the mucous membranes that line the mouth Gif tobacco is chewed) or nose if snuff is used) and even through the skin. <br><br>Our brain is made of billions of nerve cells. They communicate with each other by chemical messengers called neurotransmitters. Nicotine is one of the most powerful nerve poisons and binds stereo-selectively to nicotinic receptors located in the brain, autonomic ganglia, the medulla, neuro-muscular junctions. Located throughout the brain, they play a critical role in cognitive processes and memory.<br><br>The nicotine molecule is shaped like a neurotransmitter called acetylcholine which is involved in many functions including muscle movement, breathing, heart-rate, learning, and memory. Nicotine, because of the similar structure with acetylcholine when it gets into the brain, attaches itself to acetylcholine sites and produces toxic effects. <br><br>In high concentrations, nicotine is more deadly. In fact, one drop of purified nicotine on the tongue will kill a person. It has been used as a pesticide for centuries. Recent research studies suggest that acute nicotine administration would result in increased dopamine release from the brain, producing perceptions of pleasure and happiness, increased energy and motivation, increased alertness, increased feeling of vigor during the early phase of smoking. <br><br>However, notwithstanding these superficial effects, research shows that the relationship between smoking and memory loss is strongest in people who smoke more than 20 cigarettes each day and this is not specific to the socio-economic status, gender and a range of associated medical conditions. Smoking may speed up age-related memory loss and the details are not yet clear. Some studies suggest that repeated exposure to high nicotinic smoke related to the 'Brain-wiring' is nothing but neuro-biochemistry that deals with complex interaction among genetic experience and biochemistry of brain cells<br><br>NO' is a unique molecule that plays a role in a number of beneficial and some of the harmful brain and body mechanisms, for example, synapse formation, drug tolerance and local regulation of cerebral blood flow, Parkinson's disease, etc. It is also found that people who smoke more cigarettes a day have poorer memories in middle age than non-smokers.<br><br>Some experts say that smoking is linked to memory problems because it contributes to narrowed arteries that restrict blood flow to the brain. One of the causes of memory decline in relation to the brain function could be the nerve cell death or decreased density of interconnected neural network due to loss of dendrites, the tiny filaments which connect one nerve cell to another. Abstinence from smoking is essential, not only to avoid this systemic effect but also to reduce the ill-effects on the environment.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Egotism is the most common fault</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/egotism-is-the-most-common-fault.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/egotism-is-the-most-common-fault.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-12T15:51:52+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/23/ego-is-the-common-fault.jpg" alt="Egotism is the most common fault" />
                    Egotism is the most common fault of mankind. Product of the perfectly natural desire to display oneself, egotism, which is an exaggerated form of self-display, can take such a variety of shapes that it is not always easy to discern. Beyond any shadow of a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/23/ego-is-the-common-fault.jpg" alt="Egotism is the most common fault" />
                Egotism is the most common fault of mankind. Product of the perfectly natural desire to display oneself, egotism, which is an exaggerated form of self-display, can take such a variety of shapes that it is not always easy to discern. <br><br>Beyond any shadow of a doubt, however, it is a personal defect that ought to be constantly hunted down the scotched, for it impairs the personality, and frustrates all efforts at self-improvement.<br><br>This is the easily recognizable form of egotism that is evidenced in the person who continually talks of his own affairs. You must all have met the kind of man who is never happy when recounting his exploits and experiences in life, and whatever subject he may begin discussing you feel quite sure that he will sooner or later arrive at himself. <br><br>Although such a blatant kind of egotism is apparent to the onlooker, it may not be so easy for the egotist himself to recognize his fault. But if he can put on his guard-and it behooves each one of us to examine carefully whether we are entirely immune from this canker-there is always hope of a cure. <br><br>On the other hand, there is a type, not uncommon, which evidences its egotism by affecting a humility that is certainly not felt, and ostentatiously avoiding the use of the pronoun "I" in speech and in writing. Such affectation is an infallible sign of egotism, and it is all the more reprehensible because it is deliberately assumed by the person. <br><br>Next, we come to the individual who holds strong opinions and insists on forcing these opinions on to others. He constantly lays down the law, he knows and he jolly well insists that you shall accept his viewpoints. Here again, there is not a great difficulty in recognizing the egotistical aspect of this conduct, although it is not so easy to remove such a defect, for a person of this kind is generally possessed of a fiery temper-but again, it can be done, and recognition of the defect is the first step towards its cure. <br><br>There are two other well-known types of egotists-the over-precise person and the officious one. The former offends by his meticulous habits, his insistence on having everything just right generally connoting the way he personally wants them to be. <br><br>The officious individual succeeds in making himself most disliked because of his detestable habit of always showing or telling other people how to do things. He will glibly appeal to duty: he will continually find fault with another's way of doing things, and point out the immense superiority of his method. In his own eyes, he is always right.<br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e3740i680">SUMMARY</h2>
<br>Egotism is the commonest fault of mankind. It is an exaggerated form of self meant. An egotist thinks, talks and praises no one but himself. He never recognizes display. It is a personal defect that harms and frustrated all efforts of self-improve his faults. Affectation of humility can be another form of egotism. <br><br>The imposition of his strong opinion is the sign of an egotist. Over-precise and officious persons are two other types of egotists. The first kind of person insists on having everything just right. The second category of people find fault with others and display their superiority over others.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How does television affect our lives? </title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-does-television-affect-our-lives.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-does-television-affect-our-lives.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-11T18:33:10+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/22/tv.jpg" alt="How does television affect our lives" />
                    It can be very helpful to people who carefully choose the shows that they watch. Television can increase our knowledge of the outside world; there are high-quality programs that help us understand many fields of study science, medicine, the arts and so on. Moreover, television&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/22/tv.jpg" alt="How does television affect our lives" />
                It can be very helpful to people who carefully choose the shows that they watch. Television can increase our knowledge of the outside world; there are high-quality programs that help us understand many fields of study science, medicine, the arts and so on. <br><br>Moreover, television benefits very old people, who can't often leave the house as well as patients in hospitals. It also offers non-native speakers the advantage of daily informal language practice. They can increase their vocabulary and practice listening. On the other hand, there are several serious disadvantages of television. <br><br>Of course, it provides us with a pleasant way to relax and spend our free time, but in some countries. people watch the 'boob-tube' for an average of six hours or more a day. Many children stare at a television screen for more hours each day than they do anything else, including studying and sleeping. It's clear that the tube has a powerful influence on their lives and that its influence is often negative. <br><br>Recent studies show that after only thirty seconds of television, a person's brain relaxes' the same way that it does just before the person falls asleep. Another effect of television on the human brain is that it seems to cause poor concentration. <br><br>Children who view a lot of television can often concentrate on a subject for only fifteen to twenty minutes. They can pay attention only to the amount of time between commercials. <br><br>Another disadvantage is that television often causes people to become dissatisfied with their own lives. Real-life does not seem as exciting to these people as the lives of actors on the screen. To many people, television becomes more real than reality and their own lives seem boring. <br><br>Also, many people get upset or depressed when they can't solve problems in real life as quickly as television actors seem to. Before a child is fourteen years old, he or she views eleven thousand murders on the tube. He or she begins to believe that there is nothing strange about fights, killings and other kinds of violence. <br><br>Many studies show that people become more violent after certain programs. They may even do the things that they saw in a violent show. The most negative effect of the 'boob-tube' might be people's addiction to it. <br><br>People often feel a strange and powerful need to watch television even when they don't enjoy it. Addiction to a television screen is similar to drug or alcohol addiction. People almost never believe they are addicted.<br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e34quub40">Summary</h2>
<br>Television affects our lives in many ways. It provides knowledge of the outside world. It provides us good programs related to science, medicines, and arts. It entertains the old. But there are several serious disadvantages of television. <br><br>Most people watch TV for 6 hrs. a day. Children watch TV for more hours than they spend on studying and sleeping. Their studies suffer. People remain dissatisfied and life becomes boring. Violence, murders, and fight affect children. People get excited. They get addicted to TV. Its addiction is like drug addiction.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Pursuit of Happiness - Ultimate Goal</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/pursuit-of-happiness.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/pursuit-of-happiness.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-10T17:31:49+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/21/hapiness.jpg" alt="Pursuit of Happiness" />
                    To date, happiness has defied definition. Most people tend to equate happiness with fun, good living, plenty of money. If happiness were synonymous with all this, rich people with all their luxuries and countless parties would be perpetually happy. But in actual fact, they are,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/21/hapiness.jpg" alt="Pursuit of Happiness" />
                To date, happiness has defied definition. Most people tend to equate happiness with fun, good living, plenty of money. If happiness were synonymous with all this, rich people with all their luxuries and countless parties would be perpetually happy. But in actual fact, they are, frequently, acutely unhappy, despite their riches and ability to indulge in fun activities at will. Fun is what we experience during an act; happiness is that intangible something we experience after an act. We may have fun watching a movie, going shopping, meeting friends-these are all fun activities that afford us fleeting moments of relaxation and enjoyment. Happiness, on the other hand, is a much stronger, deeper and more abiding emotion.<br><br>If we perceive happiness as the ultimate goal, we must also devise a way to reach that goal. The way to happiness is not a smooth, broad highway along which we can cruise at a comfortable speed. It is a path through rocky and rugged terrain and the going can become very tough at times. At these times we have to roll up our sleeves and with pitchfork and shovel make our way onwards. This pursuit of happiness lasts a lifetime. Great happiness is earned only by great effort and effort not in spurts but diligent, constant effort. In this connection we are confronted with another fallacy, that fun and pleasure mean happiness and thus pain, its corollary, must be synonymous with unhappiness. But in fact, the truth is quite different. Things that bring us happiness, more often than not, involve some amount of pain. It is because of the misconception that people avoid the very endeavor that is the source of true happiness. Difficult endeavors - such as the raising of children, establishing deeper relationships with loved ones, trying to do something worthwhile in life - hold the promise of a world of happiness.<br>Happiness is not a permanent vacation. Another prevalent belief is that if one were rich enough not to have to work one would be blissfully happy. But a job is more than just a paycheque. Almost all religions teach us that work is worship. Work holds the key to happiness as doing something which increases confidence and self-worth. It brings on a feeling of satisfaction, of doing something, of contributing. Job satisfaction comes less from how much one earns than from the challenge of the job. Of course the pay-cheques count. It would be unrealistic to suggest that one could be happy without basic shelter, roaming the streets on an empty stomach.<br><br>A secret ingredient of happiness is contentment. Contentment here does not mean apathy or lack of ambition, just as commitment does not mean curtailment of freedom. Commitment teaches us to give so that we may receive and contentment helps us to cherish the gifts we have received. These things are worth a try even if they don't promise access to the pinnacle of success. Success, after all, has been described as getting what one wants, whereas happiness is liking what one gets.<br>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e3252cuo0">Summary</h2>
<br>Happiness defies definition. It is not synonymous with fun, good living or wealth. The rich are unhappy in spite of all these things. Fun activities give us only fleeting moments of enjoyment. Happiness, on the other hand, is a deeper and more abiding emotion. The way to happiness is not smooth. We have to make your own way. The pursuit of happiness is a long and lifetime experience. It is a fallacy to equate happiness with fun and pleasure. Work holds the key to happiness. Contentment brings happiness. Success means getting what one wants but happiness is liking what one gets.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Power of Faith - Faith shakes mountains</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/power-of-faith-faith-shakes-mountains.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/power-of-faith-faith-shakes-mountains.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-09T17:14:00+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/20/Faith.jpg" alt="Power of Faith" />
                    Faith is the helm of human life, which keeps it dynamic and stable even in millions of contrasts, complications. The life of the bond of faith cannot stagger. Many complications, problems, storms, storms also can not distract the person from his mission, who is walking&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/20/Faith.jpg" alt="Power of Faith" />
                Faith is the helm of human life, which keeps it dynamic and stable even in millions of contrasts, complications. The life of the bond of faith cannot stagger. Many complications, problems, storms, storms also can not distract the person from his mission, who is walking with unwavering faith in himself.<br><br>All the lamps which give light in life should be extinguished, but if the light of faith is kept burning inside the human being, it will find its own path even in the darkest darkness. All the darkness of the world disappears in front of the flame of confidence.<br><br>All the great things that have been done in the world are the works of faith. Mahatma Gandhi's strong faith made the dream of independence of the country come true. Tilak ji had said- "Swarajya is our birthright and we will keep it." His conviction later became tangible.<br><br>Lincoln wrote in his diary, and also told the people - "I have promised my God that I must complete the work of the emancipation of slaves." Despite many protests, Lincoln did that great work.<br><br>Columbus believed some cool across the vast ocean. He finally discovered America after his adventurous journey. Faith is the key to a successful life. Tolstoy wrote - "Faith is the power of life." Shakespeare said - what can "faith" not do? Faith gives us the strength and motivation to cross the skyscrapers.<br><br>Faith is the basis of all the gifts of life. Swet Marden has written- "Faith seeks the path of life that can lead us to the destination". Mahatma Gandhi said- "Faith also plays our life in the stormy sea.<br><br>Faith shakes mountains. Can transcend the vast ocean. Faith is not a soft flower that falls from the breath of ordinary air. He is immutable like the Himalayas. "<br><br>Where there is faith, all the lack of life, curse, lowliness, poverty, poverty, and poor feeling become. They do not become an impediment to the development of life. The life of most of the great men of the world proves this fact, who had little support to grow, they achieved great successes in life by their self-help. Many people became extraordinary based on their faith.<br><br>To achieve success in any field, it is necessary to have faith to move forward. If there is no power of faith behind the fulfillment of any goal, then it will be established in its initial period itself. In the absence of faith, human life becomes dry and lifeless. Inertia grabs its net.<br><br>In the absence of faith, even on the Rajpath, a man cannot move forward. Faith is not an object to be found elsewhere or a blessing of one's grace. This is the eternal truth that lies within our space.<br><br>Self-consciousness, Ajar-Akshar, All-powerful, divine form can be the basis of our faith. Man himself is the owner of renewable power and funds. Power is the third source of prosperity in human difference. When it is introduced, conviction arises.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Why Satisfaction is needed?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/why-satisfaction-is-needed.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/why-satisfaction-is-needed.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-08T14:16:21+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/19/Satisfaction.jpg" alt="Why Satisfaction is needed" />
                    Man's life is a reflection of his thoughts. Success-failure, progress-decadence, insignificance-greatness, happiness-sorrow, peace, etc. all depend on the thoughts of human beings first. Knowing the thoughts of any person, the map of his life can be easily found out. His thoughts have an important place&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/19/Satisfaction.jpg" alt="Why Satisfaction is needed" />
                <p>Man's life is a reflection of his thoughts. Success-failure, progress-decadence, insignificance-greatness, happiness-sorrow, peace, etc. all depend on the thoughts of human beings first.<br><br>Knowing the thoughts of any person, the map of his life can be easily found out. His thoughts have an important place in making a man anything cowardly, healthy-unhealthy, happy-unhappy. It means that the life of a human being is formed and worsens according to his thoughts. If good thoughts make it advanced, then inferior thoughts will fall down.<br><br>Swami Ramatirtha has said- "A man's life is like that."</p>
<p>Swami Vivekananda had said- "Heaven and hell are nowhere else, they live in our thoughts only."</p>
<p>Lord Buddha, while teaching his disciples, said- "Monks! Whatever we are in the present, our thoughts are due to us and whatever we become in the future is also due to our thoughts."<br><br>Shakespeare wrote - "Nothing is good or bad. The basis of good and evil is our thoughts."<br><br>Jesus said- "He becomes like a man has thoughts."<br><br>The famous Roman philosopher Marcus Aurelius said - "Whatever our life is, it is the result of our own thoughts."<br><br>The famous American writer Dale Carnegie, while revealing the facts based on his experiences, wrote - "The most important thing I have learned in life is that the power and importance of ideas, the power of ideas is supreme and immense."<br><br>In short, our thoughts have a major hand in conducting various activities of life. Whatever we do, we do it with the inspiration of ideas.<br>Variations and oddities seen in the world are also reflections of our thoughts.<br><br>The world is a shadow of human thoughts. For some, the world is heaven, for some, hell. For some, if the world is the face of peace, trouble, pain, etc., for someone, there is a garden full of happiness. Under the same circumstances, there is an extraordinary difference in the difference of opinion between two people with the same prosperity.<br><br>In one life, training experiences happiness, peace, satisfaction, and the other spends life in times of pain, grief. Not only this, many people are happy even after spending a life lacking difficulty, and many consider life to be hellish, even after being prosperous. One person remains contented in his circumstances and thanks God for life, the other remains dissatisfied even after getting many pleasures. Curses others, merely because of their own thoughts.<br><br>The ancient sage-sage Aranyak lived a happy and happy life after eating life of candle fruit and lived in a heavenly feeling on earth. Whereas today, there is a human who is troubled by more tribulation, disturbance, sorrow, ecstasy, even after living a life with ample comfort, prosperity, Aishwarya, scientific means. This is the result of thinking of humans.<br><br>Famous English writer Swart used to mourn each of his birthdays by wearing black and ragged clothes. He used to say- "I would not have got this life, I would not have come in the world."<br><br>In contrast, the blind poet Milton used to say- "Thank God, who gave me the priceless gift of living".<br><br>Napoleon Bonaparte said in his last days - "Sadly, I did not spend a week of my life in peace." While there was no shortage of prosperity, opulence, wealth, fame etc.<br><br>Alexander the Great also died in his last life, repenting. The basis of happiness, happiness or sorrow, grief, restlessness, remorse etc. in life are the thoughts of man himself. None other<br><br>Due to wrong thoughts, a person will be sad even in prosperity, opulence, rich life, and will experience happiness, peace and happiness even in a life which is lacking from excellent ideas.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Is it bad to take a bribe? Or offering a bribe?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/is-it-bad-to-take-a-bribe-or-offering-a-bribe.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/is-it-bad-to-take-a-bribe-or-offering-a-bribe.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-05T18:48:27+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/18/bribe.jpg" alt="Is it bad to take a bribe or bribe" />
                    In a bribery case, two sides are usually involved. One side that bribes and the other one who bribes. Both taking and giving bribes are considered criminal acts, but in this regard it is often considered a matter of dispute that in both the parties&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/18/bribe.jpg" alt="Is it bad to take a bribe or bribe" />
                In a bribery case, two sides are usually involved. One side that bribes and the other one who bribes. Both taking and giving bribes are considered criminal acts, but in this regard it is often considered a matter of dispute that in both the parties related to the act of bribery, who is responsible for this act?<br><br>We should test both sides before making a definite idea in this regard.<br><br>As far as this aspect of the idea is concerned, the responsibility of the bribe-taking party is for the work done in the transaction related to the bribe. The defendants of this party say that the bribe takers are responsible for the origin of the circumstances in which the bribe transaction becomes mandatory and it becomes the compulsion of the bribe givers.<br><br>For example- when a person has to get his work done from a government office like getting a permit or license, getting a house map approved, getting water or electricity connection etc. and when after completing all the work on his behalf as per rules It sees that the concerned file does not bother with the case, then it has to be forced and bribed.<br><br>In many offices, the situation is such that all the bribe money of the entire office is taken in one place and then the necessary work is done easily and the bribe money is distributed among the concerned people.<br><br>The argument given on the basis of this situation implies that the bribe does not want to launder his money as a bribe, but he does so only when the person doing his work does not want to work without bribe. . In this way, the bribe-taking party has the real responsibility for the circulation of the bribe transaction.<br><br>On the contrary, in relation to the party of the idea, the bribe party is responsible for the act of bribery. The proponents of this view say that the people responsible for the origin of the circumstances of the bribe transaction are the people who pay the bribe.<br><br>There are some rules for obtaining permits or licenses, getting a house map approved, obtaining a combination of water or electricity or doing other similar tasks and there is a process of their completion.<br><br>In how many days there should be a work. It is also decided, but despite all this arrangement, some people want to get their work done against the rules or - before the stipulated time and they offer bribe on their behalf, not on anyone's demand for it. , So that their work can be completed despite the rules or their work can be done before the scheduled time.<br><br>There are some such works like - contracts for government works, contracts for the supply of goods, etc., for which the contractor, etc., without any demand, gives a bribe (commission) on his own behalf.<br><br>The argument that is made on the basis of this situation means that the people who actually bribe, to prove their selfishness, make the people of the other party addicted to taking bribe. And on the basis of this reasoning, it is concluded that the actual responsibility of the circulation of the bribe transaction rests with the party paying the bribe.<br><br>But if you look a little thoughtfully, both of the above ideas are one-sided. In fact, for the practice of bribery transactions, only one party who takes or gives bribes cannot be said to be guilty or liable.<br><br>Some of the rules and circumstances of the functioning of the government are such that in which the government officials and employees are in a position to give some convenience or difficulty on their own behalf and due to this, when someone wants that facility from them, then they can pay that facility fee. Taking it as their common right.<br><br>It is therefore necessary that those situations be eliminated in which the bribe taker bribes, and the bribe taker takes the bribe.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bharat Ratna Sir Mokshagundam Visvesvaraya - A great Inspiration</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/bharat-ratna-mokshagundam-visvesvaraya.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/bharat-ratna-mokshagundam-visvesvaraya.html</id>

        <updated>2020-03-02T15:54:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/17/Bharat-Ratna-Sir-Mokshagundam-Visvesvaraya.jpeg" alt="Bharat Ratna Sir Mokshagundam Visvesvaraya" />
                    Bharat Ratna Sir Mokshagundam Visvesvaraya was born on 15 September 1861 in the village Madan Halli of Kolar district of Mysore state. His father Pandit Srinivas Shastri was a distinguished scholar, a religious but very poor and ordinary person. He did not have the funds&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/17/Bharat-Ratna-Sir-Mokshagundam-Visvesvaraya.jpeg" alt="Bharat Ratna Sir Mokshagundam Visvesvaraya" />
                <p>Bharat Ratna Sir Mokshagundam Visvesvaraya was born on 15 September 1861 in the village Madan Halli of Kolar district of Mysore state. His father Pandit Srinivas Shastri was a distinguished scholar, a religious but very poor and ordinary person.<br><br>He did not have the funds to teach his son. After studying in the village, he had to go to Bangalore for further education. He used to dine at his maternal uncle's house and pay tuition for a fee. The British Principal of the college, Charles Walters, impressed by his ability, talent and efficiency, got him enrolled in Science College of Poona and got scholarship.<br><br>In this college, he made full use of his time and got the first place in the Engineering Examination of Bombay University in 1883, as a result of which in 1884 he was awarded P.W. D. Appointed to the post of Assistant Engineer in the department. Due to his qualifications, he was about to take the post of Chief Engineer in a short time, but the British engineers opposed the posture of an Indian to the post of Chief Engineer. As a result, he was not made the Chief Engineer.<br><br>During the government service, he built the famous Sakkhar Dam in 1893 and invented the block system of irrigation and automatic sluice gates in 1899, which was praised by well-known politicians like Shri Bal Gangadhar Tilak and Mahadev Govind Ranade etc.<br><br>In 1908, he resigned from the government job. After resigning from a government job, he traveled abroad to see the industries there. In the same period, Nizam Hyderabad called itself to solve the problem of severe floods in his state. He solved the problem of flooding there by building a dam on Musi and its tributaries.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e2dc5qta2">Chief Engineer</h2>
<p>After this he was called by the Maharaja of Mysore and appointed as the Chief Engineer of the Mysore State. In 1912, the Krishnaraja Sagar Dam was built on the Kaveri River. Before the dam was built, the big British engineers had said that this dam cannot be built and crores of rupees will be wasted on it. With the construction of this dam, he got fame in the whole world.<br><br>In 1912, he was made the Diwan of the Kingdom of Mysore. He remained in the post of Diwan till 1918. During this period he started many industries and businesses there, among which Bhadravati's steel factory is notable. Established the University of Mysore in the field of education. It was the sixth university in India. People talk about their efficient and successful administration even today.<br><br>He was the first person to work on the planned economy in the country and on this subject he published his book Planned Economy for India. This was the first book of its subject published in India. He was later made the director of Tata Ispat, a post he held from 1927 to 1955.<br><br>At the age of about 90, he surprised the whole nation by constructing the Ganges bridge at Mokama near Patna. The entire country expressed respect for his merit, effort and amazing organization power. In this connection, Andhra Pradesh University in 1931, Kashi Hindu University in 1937, S.N. N. DT Women's University, Bombay and University of Mysore in 1948 awarded honorary titles.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e2dc522t1">Honors</h2>
<p>The British Government of India honored him with the title of 'Sir'. On September 7, 1955, at the Rashtrapati Bhavan Delhi, the first President of independent India, Dr. Rajendra Prasad decorated him with the "Bharat Ratna". In 1958, the premier Royal Asiatic Society of Bengal honored him with the Durga Prasad Khaitan Gold Medal.<br><br>He died on April 14, 1962 after spending a full age of one hundred and one years with great respect and effort. Indian Engineers celebrate his birthday on 15 September every year as "Engineers Day" in the memory of this great Indian engineer.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
