<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Satya Knowledge</title>
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com" />
    <updated>2020-02-26T18:59:54+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Narender Singh</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda - Which one is better?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/allopathy-homeopathy-ayurveda-which-one-is-better.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/allopathy-homeopathy-ayurveda-which-one-is-better.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:58:56+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/5/ayurveda.jpg" alt="Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda" />
                    Allopathy, homeopathy, Ayurveda and Unani are the main among the many medical practices practiced at the present time. Ayurveda (Vaidyak) was the only medical system practiced in India for a long time in all these medical practices. With the advent of the Mughals, there was&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/5/ayurveda.jpg" alt="Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda" />
                <p>Allopathy, homeopathy, Ayurveda and Unani are the main among the many medical practices practiced at the present time. Ayurveda (Vaidyak) was the only medical system practiced in India for a long time in all these medical practices.<br><br>With the advent of the Mughals, there was a practice of Arabic and Unani systems of medicine in India. Allopathy and homeopathy medical practices were also widely publicized in India upon the establishment of the English state. Among them, Ayurvedic (Vaidya), Unani (Himkat) and allopathic three medical methods are basically based on the principle of 'Reverse medicine method'. That is, to remove the disease in them, the same medicines are often consumed, which are of virtue and righteousness against the symptoms of the disease.<br><br>In the homeopathic system of medicine, to cure a disease, a medicine similar to this disease is used. Therefore, it is called 'akin treatment method'.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e20qore81">Ayurveda</h2>
<p><br>According to the Indian Ayurvedic texts, 'the treatment of poison is poison'. This means that Ayurveda medicine is based on similar medical principles, but the reality is not, because there are many drugs in it, which can be calculated under similar medicine.<br><br>Treatment of Ayurveda system includes all the principles of allopathy, homeopathy and natural medicine. This medical system is purely Indian, which is based on products derived from herbs, plants and animals in its land itself, drugs made from which do not have any side effects.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e20qnvkp0"><br>Homeopathy</h2>
<p><br>There is no name of disease in homeopathy. In this, treatment is done based on the symptoms of malformations in the body. Therefore, homeopathy can also be called 'semiotic medical science'.<br><br>The substance, by which the disease is cured, is called a medicine. But in the context of homeopathy, the substance, which has the power to both cause or destroy the disease, is called medicine.<br><br>The substances by which the medicine is prepared and consumed are called drug carriers. Although drugs are generally made from herbs, plants, minerals, fauna and germs of diseases, yet in medicine, herbs and plants have a special place.<br><br>Plants are used for the prevention of diseases in all medical systems of the world. About 80% of the world's population depends on medicines derived from plants and herbs for their health care.<br><br>Both Greek and Ayurvedic methods are formally the same, as physical condition has special significance in both. Ayurveda is a purely medical system, which is far from the influence of foreign medical practices, while Unani system of medicine originated in the country of ancient Greece, which is highly influenced by the medical practices of Persia and Africa.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>You have to dream to achieve your dreams</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/you-have-to-dream-to-achieve-your-dreams.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/you-have-to-dream-to-achieve-your-dreams.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:59:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/4/dream-achievement.jpg" alt="You have to dream to achieve your dreams" />
                    Everyone sees dreams, fantasies take birth in everyone's mind; But there are very few such people, who try to make them come true. And even less than that there are those people who can really make their dreams come true. Talking about dreams, is the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/4/dream-achievement.jpg" alt="You have to dream to achieve your dreams" />
                <p>Everyone sees dreams, fantasies take birth in everyone's mind; But there are very few such people, who try to make them come true. And even less than that there are those people who can really make their dreams come true.<br><br>Talking about dreams, is the object of dreams only? No. If there were no dreams, those who saw them would not have considered them related to real life, then we would not have been at the present peak of civilization today. It is due to these dreams that we are able to bring news of space today, are able to visit Moon, have the power to measure the world universe, etc.<br><br>Who does not know that the imaginative artist is only able to imagine the artwork in a simple piece of stone. Do not know how many people would have seen birds flying in the sky with a free spirit and thought that they too can roam like birds in the sky. But the Wright Brothers resolved to make their dream come true and they gave us airplanes. James Watt and Edison dreamed and while trying to make them come true, they gave us various tools of science.<br><br>Everything we see in the name of civilization and progress in this world is the sum of the dreams of all dreamers. Remove the accounts of dreamers from the history of the world, then see what remains to be read in history?<br><br>The dreamer is virtually the harbinger of equality. He is a seeker of realizing his dreams, doing hard labor and continuous practice, uniting his blood and sweat. It is he who has cleared the cut-off forests and has built clean roads for humanity by cutting off the paved paths. Like these seekers of human welfare, do you also wish to dream a dream of freeing humans from fear and bondage. Traditionally, what is available to man is most important in the frequency of imagination ie the power of dreaming.<br><br>According to 'Jin Khoja Tin Paiyan', who gather from their life to achieve their goal, they are grateful for their efforts. Fearful of realizing the dream of victory, Japanese youths filled the gap with their corpses and made way for Japanese troops. In 1904, it was the secret of the sensational conquest of a small country, Japan, on a large country like Russia.<br><br>Their dreams come true, who feel pleasure in working in the midst of dusty soil, mud-waste, thorn pebbles.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Who was Herodotus?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/who-was-herodotus.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/who-was-herodotus.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:47:27+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/3/Herodtus.jpg" alt="Who was Herodotus?" />
                    Herodotus is a well-known personality, the world's first historian, etc. history writer and father of history. He gave birth to the art of writing history. For this reason, he is called the 'father of history'. For the first time, he wrote the history of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/3/Herodtus.jpg" alt="Who was Herodotus?" />
                <p>Herodotus is a well-known personality, the world's first historian, etc. history writer and father of history. He gave birth to the art of writing history. For this reason, he is called the 'father of history'.<br><br>For the first time, he wrote the history of the Persian invasion of Greece in a flowing and smooth style. He described the vastness and diversity of the Persian army in a very interesting style. Herodotus was born in Asia Minor in a place called Halikarnasus, Korea, around 484 BC. He died at the age of 56 in Thuri Lutium, Italy, in about 428 BC.<br><br>Staying in Thuri, he wrote history in 9 volumes in 'Ionic' language. It has a pre-history of Persia, Lydia and Miss and specifically mentions the battle of Greece and Persia. This history dates back to 479 BC. This mainly gives us a lot of knowledge about Marathan Thermopoly and Salamis.<br><br>In this book, along with the events, there is a detailed look at the social, political, economic, cultural and religious life of the time. He spent his entire life wandering here and there like a journey.<br><br>A detailed and vivid description of history and geography is found in his writings. Along with the living and customs and conduct of the society of the then Greece, he has also depicted eminent personalities. The beautiful coordination between emotional expression and thought expression in his immortal texts is rare elsewhere.<br><br>The great historian Edward Gibbon (AD 17371794) wrote that Herodotus writes sometimes for children, sometimes for philosophers. Regarding Herodotus' extraordinary personality and immense work, Alfred D. Gadley has written a large volume called 'Herodotus' in 4 volumes, published in London in 1920-24 AD. It was in his fifty six years that he traveled to the then spinning nations.<br><br>He had said- "Travel brings perfection to life. Unreached, unknown, unseen places and things come into contact, blocking the doors of knowledge opens. The horizon of contemplation of the person becomes wider and the work of right and balanced Get inspiration for Kalap. "<br><br>In this statement, there is a part of truth, in reality, life is not complete only by studying the great books of theory. For the sake of its perfection, to give condition and form to the principle, the Kanakabha lines of behavior have to be of the nature of spiritual practice.<br><br>Walking like a 'rover', he traveled to Babylon, Egypt, Italy and Persia. Apart from this, he also visited other small African countries of the Mediterranean Sea. He wrote in history only what he saw and heard during his visit to various countries.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How long should you sleep? Requirement of Sleep</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-long-should-you-sleep-requirement-of-sleep.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-long-should-you-sleep-requirement-of-sleep.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:59:15+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/2/How-long-should-you-sleep.jpg" alt="How long should you sleep?" />
                    Sleep has an important place in a man's life - a man spends one-third of his life sleeping. Changes in sleep have an effect on human performance and health. In today's modern age, due to mental disorders like work, anger, greed, fascination, satisfaction, etc., man&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/2/How-long-should-you-sleep.jpg" alt="How long should you sleep?" />
                <p id="mcetoc_1e1rdm3k41">Sleep has an important place in a man's life - a man spends one-third of his life sleeping. Changes in sleep have an effect on human performance and health.<br><br>In today's modern age, due to mental disorders like work, anger, greed, fascination, satisfaction, etc., man has become so restless that he has a craving for natural sleep as well. Today, the disease of insomnia is spreading like a disease in the whole world. Sleeplessness has become a common complaint in today's era - regular patients come to the doctors, whose special complaint is that of sleeplessness.</p>
<p><img class="post__image align-center" src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/2/How-long-should-you-sleep.jpg" alt="" width="484" height="357"></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdmqt5c">Why a Sleep is needed?</h2>
<p id="mcetoc_1e1rdmqt5d">Sleep is a process by which the body gets rest. By deep sleep, the person finds himself stress-free, because it gives complete relief to the mind and body. When we wake up in the morning, our mind lightens and freshens the body.</p>
<p><br>If we are not able to sleep properly in the night, then we have lethargy since morning and it hurts hands and feet. The eyes remain heavy and do not feel like doing any work, that is, the next day becomes useless along with the night. Deep sleep is very important for good health, if there is no sleep for many days, then the person goes mad, the dose we get from sleep is not from anything else.<br><br>Dr. George Stevenson, an expert in mind health, says that for today's very busy and confused life, it is necessary to take care of the need and importance of sleep. At least 6 hours of sleep is necessary to maintain mental balance and health.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdo6ive">How long should you sleep?</h2>
<p>The requirement of sleep is different for different people, like- 21 hours for a child of one month, 18 hours for a child of 6 months, 12 hours for a child of 12 months, 10 hours for a child above 12 years, 16 Those above the age of 8 hours and those above 30 years should sleep for 6-7 hours and those above 40 should sleep 5-6 hours.<br><br>Those who do physical and mental labor get more sleep. In addition to insomnia, staying asleep for a long time is also a sign of laziness and is detrimental to health. According to England psychiatric doctor Zomz, excess sleep affects blood flow, ie it slows down. Heart diseases can occur as a result, the lungs become weak.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdrd4ki">Using Sleeping Pills</h2>
<p>It is not good to resort to drugs to get good sleep. Eating sleeping pills adversely affects health.<br><br>Regarding the consumption of sleeping pills, a famous doctor says that you get five hours of sleep and if you consume the sleeping pill daily to make it seven hours, then some days you will get seven hours of sleep, But after some time you will also have trouble sleeping for five hours. Scientists have proved that sleeping with the head in the east direction leads to peaceful and happy sleep.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cosmopolitanism instead of Patriotism</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:46:51+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/1/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.jpg" alt="Cosmopolitanism instead of Patriotism" />
                    Today the world is sitting on the volcano of world destruction. Mankind has firmly confirmed its apocalypse. Molecule bombs, atomic bombs, cobalt bombs, hydrogen bombs and biological bombs guarantee the death of all living organisms on Earth today. We have made 'guided' missiles, but we&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/1/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.jpg" alt="Cosmopolitanism instead of Patriotism" />
                <p>Today the world is sitting on the volcano of world destruction. Mankind has firmly confirmed its apocalypse. Molecule bombs, atomic bombs, cobalt bombs, hydrogen bombs and biological bombs guarantee the death of all living organisms on Earth today.</p>
<p><br><br>We have made 'guided' missiles, but we ourselves are becoming missguided. Today, the world's defense expenditure has reached about 2 billion dollars annually. Around 2 crore people are engaged in military and 200 million people are engaged in semi-military operations.<br><br>The starvation prevailing in the world can be eliminated with only one percent contribution of this huge expenditure. The world government is absolutely essential to end the blind race for justice and armament of this forest.<br><br>Today, the world is in the grip of economic inequality. On the other hand, 15% of the developed population of the world is spending 60% of the total world income on opulence and luxury, on the other hand, the people of the developing countries are forced to live an animal life. The future of their children is dark. Far from education and employment, basic amenities like food, clothing and housing are not available to them.<br><br>Kalahandi district of Odisha lost many lives due to non-availability of drinking water. Similarly, in 1987, hundreds of people in Kenya (Africa) fell victim to starvation. By controlling these economic inequalities through the World Government, basic amenities can be made available to the world public. Similarly, through the world government, the prevailing caste-discrimination, apartheid and autocratic and autocratic rule in the world can be completely destroyed.<br><br>Many scholars envisaged world government from time to time. Among them are Henry IV, William Penn, Emerick Krause, Pierre Dubi, Kant, Russo, Mahatma Gandhi, Sarvepalli Dr. Radhakrishnan, etc. In 1919, Clarence Street mentioned the world government in the second chapter of his book 'Union Now'.<br><br>In this way, Arnold Tynby in his book, 'Have Man a Future', has formed the administrative, executive and judiciary of the world government. The simplest and most practical way to form a world government is to develop the United Nations into a world government. Accepting its federal form, the General Assembly should be given the shape of the World Parliament, the Security Council as the World Executive and the International Court as the World Court.<br><br>Also, in order to make the world government successful and effective, it is necessary that all nations limit their sovereignty and make the world government sovereign. They should hand over the responsibility of their unity and integrity to him. All nations should think above the narrow mindset of language, religion, caste and community and propagate cosmopolitanism instead of patriotism in the country.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
