<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Satya Knowledge</title>
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com" />
    <updated>2020-02-29T16:27:50+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Narender Singh</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Why Honesty is naked?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/why-honesty-is-naked.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/why-honesty-is-naked.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-29T16:20:36+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/16/plato-quote.jpg" alt="Honesty vs dishonesty" />
                    Our elders often teach us that we should always be honest, conduct truth, perform our duty and help the weak and poor. In fact, these are some moral beliefs, which we have considered to be very important for our lives and whose official practice we&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/16/plato-quote.jpg" alt="Honesty vs dishonesty" />
                <p>Our elders often teach us that we should always be honest, conduct truth, perform our duty and help the weak and poor.<br><br>In fact, these are some moral beliefs, which we have considered to be very important for our lives and whose official practice we have been trying to do. The reason we have done this has been that we consider these moral beliefs to be a means of making our life happy and believe that without them human life becomes distorted and painful.<br><br>But on the contrary, when we see that those who live a life of untruth, cheating and dishonesty are not happy, but vice versa, then it becomes questionable that moral beliefs like truth, duty and honesty etc. should be given to us. Whether to base Because it is a matter of experience that every person in the world shows truth, truthfulness and honesty for goodness and it says that these should be the basis of our life.<br><br>But in actual practice, innumerable people appear to be giving up these ideals when they see that walking on them does not solve the real problems of life and people who do not care for them lead a more happy life in the world. Why do most people not accept truth and honesty? In this context, a story related to dishonesty and honesty is very relevant.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e288nufp1">Honesty and Dishonesty</h2>
<p>It is said that once honesty and dishonesty went to bathe in a river. After taking off their clothes for bathing, both of them took a dip in the river with the race to take a long dip. Dishonesty came out of the water quickly due to its tendency and after wearing the clothes of honesty, went away from there.<br><br>When honesty later came out of the water and could not find her clothes on the banks of the river, she was confused because she did not want to be dishonest by wearing Dishonesty's clothes. In such a situation, he thought to be nude.<br><br>It is said that since then, honesty is naked and her clothes have been worn by Dishonesty. As a result, people who want to avoid nudity, adopt Dishonesty wearing honesty clothes and remain attuned to them as long as they can recognize the reality of Dishonesty. Because many problems of people are easily solved with the help of it.<br><br>According to the story, this is the reason that honesty has fallen alone in the world and there are very few people to adopt it; Whereas people who adopt dishonesty and live with it are numerous and they do not consider it bad but good.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to avoid evil? - Great Thoughts</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-to-avoid-evil.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-to-avoid-evil.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-28T18:23:51+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/15/avoid-evil.jpg" alt="How to avoid evil" />
                    The famous scholar Tacitus has said that "As long as humans live, evil will remain." The greatest feature of evil is that it forces the holder to find his / her ambition elsewhere. As a result, no one is able to see their evils and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/15/avoid-evil.jpg" alt="How to avoid evil" />
                The famous scholar Tacitus has said that "As long as humans live, evil will remain."<br><br>The greatest feature of evil is that it forces the holder to find his / her ambition elsewhere. As a result, no one is able to see their evils and does not even try to remove them. As a result, he continues to provide the birth protection of his evildoer and his unrestrained side continues to be confirmed.<br><br>Per-dosha philosophy means that a person who is busy in seeing the evil of others, remains ignorant of the insects inside him towards his evil. This is why it is said that Dosh Darshan is the biggest flaw or evil But the situation is such that no one blames himself in 99 percent of situations, no matter how big his mistake is.<br><br>Swami Ramathirtha says that 'अपनी आँख में शहतीर देख पाने की अपेक्षा दूसरों की आँख में तिनका देख लेना सरल है.'<br><br>Therefore, we should first avoid the evil called dosha-darshan and the simple solution to this is that we should practice watching our evils. We will see that the evils that we see in other people are present in us. Saint Kabir Das has said that<br><br>बुरा जो देखन मैं चला, बुरा मिला न कोय । जो दिल खोजा आपना, मुझसा बुरा न कोय ॥<br><br>Therefore, if we know our evils and try to remove them one by one, we will do a lot of work in life and ourselves will also become a good and big person. As soon as we start looking towards our faults or our evils, as we start to consider others as bad and blame them for our sufferings.<br><br>A famous thinker has spoken of great importance in this context - "Ordinary people blame each other for their evil."<br><br>Thinking of evil in any form casts a dark shadow on the mind. Clashes and discord arise due to the thought of evil or its discussion. The action of which karma results in discord and affliction, there is no benefit, but only loss. The best and best way to avoid evils is not to discuss them, and try to remove our evils one by one. Goods will be reputed by them in their spaces.<br><br>Acharya Vinoba Bhave has said that "Bad things should be forgotten. If we keep looking at the bad things, then people will become cruel."<br><br>Benjamin Franklin has also said- "Let your evils die before you."
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Should You go to England to Study?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/study-in-england.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/study-in-england.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-28T18:47:46+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/14/study-in-england.jpg" alt="Should You go to England for Study?" />
                    It is natural for talented and talented students to have an ambition to get higher education in foreign universities and institutes. In the absence of sufficient information and proper guidelines, the idea of ​​getting education abroad from them seems like breaking stars from the sky,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/14/study-in-england.jpg" alt="Should You go to England for Study?" />
                It is natural for talented and talented students to have an ambition to get higher education in foreign universities and institutes. In the absence of sufficient information and proper guidelines, the idea of ​​getting education abroad from them seems like breaking stars from the sky, but all this is not true.<br><br>Talented and promising students who are not very rich and want to pursue higher education abroad, can know the way forward for their future by learning about the feelings of scholarship in foreign universities and institutes. Come, give you some useful information in this subject, so that you too can fulfill your dream of getting higher education abroad.<br><br>The education system of India is very much in line with the education system of England. Apart from this, a large number of people of Indian origin are inhabited there. That's why Indian people often like to go to England more for studies and it is often that after completing their education most of the people also work there.<br><br>The same happens to Indians known for research and higher education. Perhaps this is the reason that a large number of engineers, doctors and other trained human resources working in England belong to people of Indian origin. There are some who really want to return home, but do not have the courage to end the facilities available in England, the social environment and the relationships of their children's British life in one stroke. Hence, even if the unsolicited get away from their motherland.<br><br>There are many types of misconceptions in England about the system of foreign students, especially Indian students, to get education. Like some people say that to get education in England, English language proficiency is necessary. In the opinion of such people, English is the most difficult in the UK and the level of English language is also important along with education there.<br><br>There is no obstacle for students studying in convent or other public schools in India, but students studying through Hindi medium must face many difficulties there.<br><br>There are a total of 47 universities and institutes for higher education in England, many of which provide scholarships to foreign students by providing scholarships. Apart from this, there are also scholarships from Commonwealth countries and the British Council.<br><br>In universities here, applications for admission to postgraduate level courses are accepted through the Education Officer of the Indian Embassy in UK.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Historical Facts about Kashmir Issue</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/historical-facts-about-kashmir-issue.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/historical-facts-about-kashmir-issue.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-27T19:36:24+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/10/kashmir-issue.jpg" alt="Historical Facts about Kashmir Issue" />
                    Today no one can deny the historical fact that the Kashmir problem was born due to the wrong decisions of Pt. Jawaharlal Nehru, the first Prime Minister of India. When the British Government passed the Indian Independence Act 1947 to liberate Hindustan, it gave the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/10/kashmir-issue.jpg" alt="Historical Facts about Kashmir Issue" />
                <p>Today no one can deny the historical fact that the Kashmir problem was born due to the wrong decisions of Pt. Jawaharlal Nehru, the first Prime Minister of India. When the British Government passed the Indian Independence Act 1947 to liberate Hindustan, it gave the right to join or remain independent in India or Pakistan, which ruled by the King Maharajas.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e23dv7sq2">Maharaja Harisingh</h2>
<p>As a result, at that time, Maharaja Harisingh of Jammu and Kashmir refused to join India or Pakistan and announced that he would compromise with both countries - Pakistan and Hindustan - by remaining independent. On 14 August 1947, Pakistan was declared and India became independent on 15 August 1947.<br><br>Pakistani rulers have since forced Maharaja Harisingh to merge Jammu and Kashmir with Pakistan, but when they were not ready for it, he first made an economic blockade of Janmu-Kashmir and then made a confession on October 22, 1947. Suddenly attacked the state under cover.<br><br>Two days after the Pakistani attack on Jammu and Kashmir, on 24 October 1947, Maharaja Harisingh declared an unconditional merger of Jammu Kashmir with India and asked for military assistance from India, but since India had no air service at the time, Army sent to Kashmir by private air services ships by Nehru government. In doing so, it took 3 days for the Indian Army to reach Kashmir and as a result, in these five days, Pakistani forces got the opportunity to wreak havoc in the state to a great extent.<br><br>Jammu and Kashmir became a legal part of India on 27 October 1947 after Maharaja Harisingh accepted the merger proposal. But the Nehru government nevertheless assured that upon the establishment of peace, the desire of the people of the state to meet in India or Pakistan would be ascertained.<br><br>If seen from the perspective of today, the Nehru government was a huge mistake like the Himalayas. After this, a wrong decision was made that even after the merger was completed in terms of law, Article 370 was added to the Constitution of India and gave Kashmir a separate status from other states of India. Sheikh Abdullah was made Prime Minister and Harisingh's son Karn Singh was made Sadar princely state by removing Maharaja Harisingh from the throne.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e23du6q20">Sardar Patel opposes this</h2>
<p>Sardar Patel, opposing this, suggested that the refugees who had come to desolate from Pakistan should be settled in Jammu and Kashmir. But Sheikh Abdullah was not ready for this, so even Pt. Nehru did not like it. It would be ironic that on the basis of Maharaja Harisingh's proposal, even after the merger of Kashmir with India was completed, under Article 370 of the Constitution, Kashmir maintained a separate existence from other states.<br><br>Can a country have two legislations, two marks and two heads? India was the first country in the world where this happened. The flag of Jammu Kashmir is different till date. As long as Sheikh Abdullah remained in power, he was called Prime Minister, while all other states had chief ministers. All the states of the country had governors, Kashmir alone was a princely state.<br><br>Not only this, the citizens of India could not go to Kashmir without a visa and the decisions of the Supreme Court of India were also not applicable there. All these things gave the world an opportunity to understand and believe that Kashmir is different from India. Another major mistake of Pandit Nehru was that he took the attack of Pakistan to the United Nations, due to which he is still undecided.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dalai Lama - Ocean of Wisdom</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/dalai-lama-ocean-of-wisdom.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/dalai-lama-ocean-of-wisdom.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-27T19:03:45+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/9/dalai-lama.jpg" alt="Dalai Lama - Ocean of Wisdom" />
                    The Dalai Lama is the 14th Dharma Guru of the ancient tradition of Tibet. The Dalai Lama is a title, meaning the ocean of wisdom. For the first time, this title was given to Sonam Gyats in the late 16th century by King Altan Khan&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/9/dalai-lama.jpg" alt="Dalai Lama - Ocean of Wisdom" />
                The Dalai Lama is the 14th Dharma Guru of the ancient tradition of Tibet. The Dalai Lama is a title, meaning the ocean of wisdom. For the first time, this title was given to Sonam Gyats in the late 16th century by King Altan Khan Aim of Mongolia in his honor.<br><br>Who knew that this child of a poor peasant family of the Adi province of eastern Tibet would be worshiped as a 'living Buddha' by the Buddhist religions of the world.<br><br>The original name of the Dalai Lama is Tenzin Gyatso. At the age of two, Tibetans began to consider him as an incarnation of the previous Dalai Lama. Even today, 60 million Tibetans consider him the avatar of Avalokiteshvara (chain regi), the god of mercy, but the very humble and self-conscious Dalai Lama considers himself nothing more than a Buddhist monk.<br><br>When the army of Mao-tse-Tung invaded Tibet in 1950, at the age of 15, the Dalai Lama had to go to Beijing and negotiate a settlement with Mao. The freedom movement of Tibet against Chinese imperialism had failed in 1959, when the Dalai Lama was forced to take refuge in India. Since then, he is living in an area called 'Dharamshala' in Himachal Pradesh with one lakh Tibetan refugees.<br><br>Dharamshala as 'Nanhe Lhasa' (Lhasa is the capital of Tibet) has become the headquarters of the Dalai Lama's exiled government today. Mahatma Gandhi is the inspiration of the Dalai Lama. He has unwavering faith in peace and non-violence.<br><br>The Dalai Lama says- "I have full faith in Mahatma Gandhi's path of non-violence. I have always been inspired by this and I hope that the question of Tibet will be resolved. There is no other way than non-violence."<br><br>There is no doubt that after receiving the Nobel Peace Prize, the Dalai Lama's international image as a peaceful and non-violent leader has been created. The Dalai Lama himself accepts this fact and says, as a monk, I should not be influenced by the awards.
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How was the calendar invented?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-was-the-calendar-invented.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-was-the-calendar-invented.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-27T18:52:13+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/8/evolution-of-calendar.jpg" alt="How was the calendar invented?" />
                    The credit for starting the calendar goes to India, because the first mention of the calendar in India is 5000 BC. The calendar of babylon is mentioned in 4700 BC, and the Babylonians first made months based on astronomy, excluding superstition. Calendar means division of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/8/evolution-of-calendar.jpg" alt="How was the calendar invented?" />
                <p>The credit for starting the calendar goes to India, because the first mention of the calendar in India is 5000 BC. The calendar of babylon is mentioned in 4700 BC, and the Babylonians first made months based on astronomy, excluding superstition.<br><br>Calendar means division of days. This word is from the Greek 'calendae' which means the first day of the Roman month, and is formed by adding 'r'. All the important dates of that month were announced in Rome on the first day of the month. Actually the calendar is not the gift of any country. Different countries have contributed to it from time to time. Egypt first created the calendar.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e23coei31">Evolution of Calendar</h2>
<p><br>It is believed that there were 12 months in this calendar. The number of days was thirty in all the months. Each month was divided into ten days of ten days each. Thousands of years ago, possibly the Egyptians understood the importance of the 'decimal system'. Days were known by number. At the end of the year, the days, days and nights were equal, five days were added, but they were not counted in the year.<br><br>Like Egypt, Greece and China also made their own calendars, but the creation of the most popular calendar in the world is attributed to the ruler of Rome, Julius Caesar. He made certain amendments in the Egyptian calendar with the help of Egyptian astronomer 'Secci Jens' and gave the world a new calendar.<br><br>He divided the days of the Egyptian calendar into odd-numbered months today. The name of the month of Quintalus was changed to July, considering its name as Aadhaar. In the normal year, keep 29 days in February and 30 days in February in the leap year. It was decided not to start the new year from March but to accept it from January 1. This revision was done in 46 BC.<br><br>Julius Caesar considered the solar year to be 365–25 days. Therefore, he decided to consider every fourth year as leap year. Julius Caesar did not make any changes in the Egyptian week. In the year 321, the Roman Emperor 'Constantine' made a change in the week. He made the week seven days by decree.<br><br>The Julian calendar was mainly revised twice. The first amendment was made eight years before Christ by the Emperor August Caesar. They wanted to rename the eighth month as August on the basis of their name; Therefore, he changed the name of 'Sexatillas' to August by the ordinance of the Roman Senate.<br><br>Due to Julius Caesar having 31 days in the month of July, 30 days in the month of Sextillas were considered 31 days in the month of August. It was taken one day from the month of February. Since then, 28 days started in February and 29 days in leap year in the normal year.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>I serve that God by serving these millions - Mahatma Gautam</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/i-serve-that-god-by-serving-these-millions-mahatma-gautam.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/i-serve-that-god-by-serving-these-millions-mahatma-gautam.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-27T16:00:02+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/7/serving-people.jpg" alt="I serve that God by serving these millions - Mahatma Gautam" />
                    "Service is the natural instinct of man. Service is the basis of his life." The meaning of this statement of the novel Emperor Munshi Premchand begins to be understood upon the arrival of youth, when the person starts getting entangled in the house of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/7/serving-people.jpg" alt="I serve that God by serving these millions - Mahatma Gautam" />
                <p>"Service is the natural instinct of man. Service is the basis of his life." The meaning of this statement of the novel Emperor Munshi Premchand begins to be understood upon the arrival of youth, when the person starts getting entangled in the house of the family. He is forced to do a lot for his wife and children with a stoic spirit, not because of any external pressure but because of inner motivation.<br><br>The law of service in nature seems to work at an unforeseen pace. The sun and the moon provide light and warmth to the world, the air provides a breath of life, the earth gives a place to live, trees give shade, etc.<br><br>They do not do this life with the feeling of any reward. They do this only by their innate nature. We also help the oppressed with internal stimulation only.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e23343d70">Service Spirit is needed</h2>
<p>When we pick up an injured or unconscious person lying in a corner of the road and take us to the hospital, do we think that he will give us the reward for being good or that he ever took us to the hospital if we are injured or unconscious? When this service spirit is developed continuously, then it becomes the virtue of the person and the personality of the society.<br><br>People who have service and do not make selfishness the goal of life, there is no shortage of people who support them. According to Goswami Tulsidas, 'Seva-dharma kathin jag jana' means that the world knows that serving is very difficult work.<br><br>Self-sacrifice and disobedience are absolutely essential in service. A person without ego, every particle of the world; He thinks like himself, everyone is selfish for him. At least he does not consider anyone younger than himself, hey, frivolous or inferior and feels oneness with pranamatra.<br><br>He performs each of his tasks with a sense of service to the Supreme Lord. Through service, he has self-realization or vision of God. In the context of self-interview, service is both elaborate means and practicable, that is, the fruit of service is nothing but the enjoyment received by the service. Just as devotion results in devotion.<br><br>The service of the creatures of the world is the true service-worship and devotion of the world. It is written in the scripture of Christians that if you cannot love your neighbor, whom you see regularly, then how will you be able to love the God whom you have never seen?<br><br>Mahatma Gautam has said in very clear words that the one who has to serve me, should serve the victims. Mahatma Gandhi has also said that God is sitting in the hearts of millions of the dumb; I do not believe in any other God except Him. I serve that God by serving these millions.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Stop Eating Jaggery - An Inspirational Short Story</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/stop-eating-jaggery-an-inspirational-short-story.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/stop-eating-jaggery-an-inspirational-short-story.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-27T15:48:53+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/6/an-inspirational-story-stop-eating-jaggery.jpg" alt="Stop Eating Jaggery - An Inspirational Short Story" />
                    A woman went to a monk and said- Baba, my son eats jaggery a lot. Because of this it remains unhealthy. Request that you explain this and get rid of this habit. The monk said come a week later. The woman arrived a week later&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/6/an-inspirational-story-stop-eating-jaggery.jpg" alt="Stop Eating Jaggery - An Inspirational Short Story" />
                <p>A woman went to a monk and said- Baba, my son eats jaggery a lot. Because of this it remains unhealthy. Request that you explain this and get rid of this habit.<br><br>The monk said come a week later. The woman arrived a week later with her son. The monk then said to come after a week. Thus four weeks passed. When the parents reached the fifth time, the monk asked the son - why do you eat so much jaggery? Stop eating jaggery. The son stopped eating jaggery from the next day.<br><br>Mother went and expressed heartfelt gratitude to the monk and asked - Baba why did you take five weeks to say this? Baba smilingly replied - I used to eat jaggery myself. Till I do not stop eating jaggery on my own, then from which mouth would I ask the child to stop eating jaggery. In five weeks, I had stopped eating good food. For this reason, my statement affected the child and his desired result was revealed.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e2322g9b1">Moral of the Story</h2>
<p><br>We can see for ourselves that our leaders regularly give big lectures, but they have no effect, because there is no moral force behind the speaker's speech. On the contrary, when Mahatma Gandhi used to say these things, thousands of people agreed to obey him and were ready to sacrifice everything. Mahatma ji used to say what he used to do and do what he used to say.<br><br>By working according to the statement, the self-power that is created in a person's speech, through this, the force and effectiveness are added to the speech. People who do good things and do not behave accordingly.<br><br>The lack of harmony between words and actions makes the resolving power weak, as a result of which the moral strength and confidence of the person is eroded and he remains as a mere voice. Such a person can be attractive like a flower of seminal flower, but they are completely immaterial. They are of no use to society.<br><br>In the present tense, everyone is heard saying that visions of truth have become rare nowadays, lie has spoken, character has fallen: etc. After considering it, the reason for all these anomalies and inconsistencies is easily understood.<br><br>Everyone expects truth from others and does not speak the truth himself. That is, each person reserves the responsibility of ethics to other persons by keeping false information safe for himself.<br><br>Consider for yourself what authority a father who drinks alcohol can tell his son to abstain from? Leaders who violate the rules of law in Parliament and Vidhan Sabha and take the path of violence to make their point heard. Why can we hope that our youth will be disciplined and put their power in creative works.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda - Which one is better?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/allopathy-homeopathy-ayurveda-which-one-is-better.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/allopathy-homeopathy-ayurveda-which-one-is-better.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:58:56+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/5/ayurveda.jpg" alt="Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda" />
                    Allopathy, homeopathy, Ayurveda and Unani are the main among the many medical practices practiced at the present time. Ayurveda (Vaidyak) was the only medical system practiced in India for a long time in all these medical practices. With the advent of the Mughals, there was&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/5/ayurveda.jpg" alt="Allopathy, Homeopathy, Ayurveda" />
                <p>Allopathy, homeopathy, Ayurveda and Unani are the main among the many medical practices practiced at the present time. Ayurveda (Vaidyak) was the only medical system practiced in India for a long time in all these medical practices.<br><br>With the advent of the Mughals, there was a practice of Arabic and Unani systems of medicine in India. Allopathy and homeopathy medical practices were also widely publicized in India upon the establishment of the English state. Among them, Ayurvedic (Vaidya), Unani (Himkat) and allopathic three medical methods are basically based on the principle of 'Reverse medicine method'. That is, to remove the disease in them, the same medicines are often consumed, which are of virtue and righteousness against the symptoms of the disease.<br><br>In the homeopathic system of medicine, to cure a disease, a medicine similar to this disease is used. Therefore, it is called 'akin treatment method'.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e20qore81">Ayurveda</h2>
<p><br>According to the Indian Ayurvedic texts, 'the treatment of poison is poison'. This means that Ayurveda medicine is based on similar medical principles, but the reality is not, because there are many drugs in it, which can be calculated under similar medicine.<br><br>Treatment of Ayurveda system includes all the principles of allopathy, homeopathy and natural medicine. This medical system is purely Indian, which is based on products derived from herbs, plants and animals in its land itself, drugs made from which do not have any side effects.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e20qnvkp0"><br>Homeopathy</h2>
<p><br>There is no name of disease in homeopathy. In this, treatment is done based on the symptoms of malformations in the body. Therefore, homeopathy can also be called 'semiotic medical science'.<br><br>The substance, by which the disease is cured, is called a medicine. But in the context of homeopathy, the substance, which has the power to both cause or destroy the disease, is called medicine.<br><br>The substances by which the medicine is prepared and consumed are called drug carriers. Although drugs are generally made from herbs, plants, minerals, fauna and germs of diseases, yet in medicine, herbs and plants have a special place.<br><br>Plants are used for the prevention of diseases in all medical systems of the world. About 80% of the world's population depends on medicines derived from plants and herbs for their health care.<br><br>Both Greek and Ayurvedic methods are formally the same, as physical condition has special significance in both. Ayurveda is a purely medical system, which is far from the influence of foreign medical practices, while Unani system of medicine originated in the country of ancient Greece, which is highly influenced by the medical practices of Persia and Africa.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>You have to dream to achieve your dreams</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/you-have-to-dream-to-achieve-your-dreams.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/you-have-to-dream-to-achieve-your-dreams.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-26T18:59:05+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/4/dream-achievement.jpg" alt="You have to dream to achieve your dreams" />
                    Everyone sees dreams, fantasies take birth in everyone's mind; But there are very few such people, who try to make them come true. And even less than that there are those people who can really make their dreams come true. Talking about dreams, is the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/4/dream-achievement.jpg" alt="You have to dream to achieve your dreams" />
                <p>Everyone sees dreams, fantasies take birth in everyone's mind; But there are very few such people, who try to make them come true. And even less than that there are those people who can really make their dreams come true.<br><br>Talking about dreams, is the object of dreams only? No. If there were no dreams, those who saw them would not have considered them related to real life, then we would not have been at the present peak of civilization today. It is due to these dreams that we are able to bring news of space today, are able to visit Moon, have the power to measure the world universe, etc.<br><br>Who does not know that the imaginative artist is only able to imagine the artwork in a simple piece of stone. Do not know how many people would have seen birds flying in the sky with a free spirit and thought that they too can roam like birds in the sky. But the Wright Brothers resolved to make their dream come true and they gave us airplanes. James Watt and Edison dreamed and while trying to make them come true, they gave us various tools of science.<br><br>Everything we see in the name of civilization and progress in this world is the sum of the dreams of all dreamers. Remove the accounts of dreamers from the history of the world, then see what remains to be read in history?<br><br>The dreamer is virtually the harbinger of equality. He is a seeker of realizing his dreams, doing hard labor and continuous practice, uniting his blood and sweat. It is he who has cleared the cut-off forests and has built clean roads for humanity by cutting off the paved paths. Like these seekers of human welfare, do you also wish to dream a dream of freeing humans from fear and bondage. Traditionally, what is available to man is most important in the frequency of imagination ie the power of dreaming.<br><br>According to 'Jin Khoja Tin Paiyan', who gather from their life to achieve their goal, they are grateful for their efforts. Fearful of realizing the dream of victory, Japanese youths filled the gap with their corpses and made way for Japanese troops. In 1904, it was the secret of the sensational conquest of a small country, Japan, on a large country like Russia.<br><br>Their dreams come true, who feel pleasure in working in the midst of dusty soil, mud-waste, thorn pebbles.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
