<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Satya Knowledge</title>
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com" />
    <updated>2020-02-24T16:37:23+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Narender Singh</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How long should you sleep? Requirement of Sleep</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-long-should-you-sleep-requirement-of-sleep.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/how-long-should-you-sleep-requirement-of-sleep.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-24T16:36:37+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Sleep has an important place in a man's life - a man spends one-third of his life sleeping. Changes in sleep have an effect on human performance and health. In today's modern age, due to mental disorders like work, anger, greed, fascination, satisfaction, etc., man&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p id="mcetoc_1e1rdm3k41">Sleep has an important place in a man's life - a man spends one-third of his life sleeping. Changes in sleep have an effect on human performance and health.<br><br>In today's modern age, due to mental disorders like work, anger, greed, fascination, satisfaction, etc., man has become so restless that he has a craving for natural sleep as well. Today, the disease of insomnia is spreading like a disease in the whole world. Sleeplessness has become a common complaint in today's era - regular patients come to the doctors, whose special complaint is that of sleeplessness.</p>
<p><img class="post__image align-center" src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/2/How-long-should-you-sleep.jpg" alt="" width="484" height="357"></p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdmqt5c">Why a Sleep is needed?</h2>
<p id="mcetoc_1e1rdmqt5d">Sleep is a process by which the body gets rest. By deep sleep, the person finds himself stress-free, because it gives complete relief to the mind and body. When we wake up in the morning, our mind lightens and freshens the body.</p>
<p><br>If we are not able to sleep properly in the night, then we have lethargy since morning and it hurts hands and feet. The eyes remain heavy and do not feel like doing any work, that is, the next day becomes useless along with the night. Deep sleep is very important for good health, if there is no sleep for many days, then the person goes mad, the dose we get from sleep is not from anything else.<br><br>Dr. George Stevenson, an expert in mind health, says that for today's very busy and confused life, it is necessary to take care of the need and importance of sleep. At least 6 hours of sleep is necessary to maintain mental balance and health.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdo6ive">How long should you sleep?</h2>
<p>The requirement of sleep is different for different people, like- 21 hours for a child of one month, 18 hours for a child of 6 months, 12 hours for a child of 12 months, 10 hours for a child above 12 years, 16 Those above the age of 8 hours and those above 30 years should sleep for 6-7 hours and those above 40 should sleep 5-6 hours.<br><br>Those who do physical and mental labor get more sleep. In addition to insomnia, staying asleep for a long time is also a sign of laziness and is detrimental to health. According to England psychiatric doctor Zomz, excess sleep affects blood flow, ie it slows down. Heart diseases can occur as a result, the lungs become weak.</p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1e1rdrd4ki">Using Sleeping Pills</h2>
<p>It is not good to resort to drugs to get good sleep. Eating sleeping pills adversely affects health.<br><br>Regarding the consumption of sleeping pills, a famous doctor says that you get five hours of sleep and if you consume the sleeping pill daily to make it seven hours, then some days you will get seven hours of sleep, But after some time you will also have trouble sleeping for five hours. Scientists have proved that sleeping with the head in the east direction leads to peaceful and happy sleep.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Cosmopolitanism instead of Patriotism</title>
        <author>
            <name>Narender Singh</name>
        </author>
        <link href="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.html"/>
        <id>http://www.satyaknowledge.com/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.html</id>

        <updated>2020-02-24T16:18:28+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Today the world is sitting on the volcano of world destruction. Mankind has firmly confirmed its apocalypse. Molecule bombs, atomic bombs, cobalt bombs, hydrogen bombs and biological bombs guarantee the death of all living organisms on Earth today. We have made 'guided' missiles, but we&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Today the world is sitting on the volcano of world destruction. Mankind has firmly confirmed its apocalypse. Molecule bombs, atomic bombs, cobalt bombs, hydrogen bombs and biological bombs guarantee the death of all living organisms on Earth today.</p>
<p><br><img class="post__image--center" src="http://www.satyaknowledge.com/media/posts/1/cosmopolitanism-instead-of-patriotism.jpg" alt="" width="533" height="400"><br>We have made 'guided' missiles, but we ourselves are becoming missguided. Today, the world's defense expenditure has reached about 2 billion dollars annually. Around 2 crore people are engaged in military and 200 million people are engaged in semi-military operations.<br><br>The starvation prevailing in the world can be eliminated with only one percent contribution of this huge expenditure. The world government is absolutely essential to end the blind race for justice and armament of this forest.<br><br>Today, the world is in the grip of economic inequality. On the other hand, 15% of the developed population of the world is spending 60% of the total world income on opulence and luxury, on the other hand, the people of the developing countries are forced to live an animal life. The future of their children is dark. Far from education and employment, basic amenities like food, clothing and housing are not available to them.<br><br>Kalahandi district of Odisha lost many lives due to non-availability of drinking water. Similarly, in 1987, hundreds of people in Kenya (Africa) fell victim to starvation. By controlling these economic inequalities through the World Government, basic amenities can be made available to the world public. Similarly, through the world government, the prevailing caste-discrimination, apartheid and autocratic and autocratic rule in the world can be completely destroyed.<br><br>Many scholars envisaged world government from time to time. Among them are Henry IV, William Penn, Emerick Krause, Pierre Dubi, Kant, Russo, Mahatma Gandhi, Sarvepalli Dr. Radhakrishnan, etc. In 1919, Clarence Street mentioned the world government in the second chapter of his book 'Union Now'.<br><br>In this way, Arnold Tynby in his book, 'Have Man a Future', has formed the administrative, executive and judiciary of the world government. The simplest and most practical way to form a world government is to develop the United Nations into a world government. Accepting its federal form, the General Assembly should be given the shape of the World Parliament, the Security Council as the World Executive and the International Court as the World Court.<br><br>Also, in order to make the world government successful and effective, it is necessary that all nations limit their sovereignty and make the world government sovereign. They should hand over the responsibility of their unity and integrity to him. All nations should think above the narrow mindset of language, religion, caste and community and propagate cosmopolitanism instead of patriotism in the country.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
